A Guide to the Papers of Edmund S. Campbell
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Museum File (general) 1938-1939, 2 items (Box 26)
- Museum of Fine Arts 1942-1943, ca. 25 items (Box 26)
- Museum (Grounds and Planting) 1935-1938, ca. 25 items (Box 26)
- Museum, Incription to 1934-1936, ca. 20 items (Box 26)
- Museum of Modern Art 1935-1938, ca. 10 items (Box 26)
- Museum (newspaper clippings) 1935-1936, ca. 35 items (Box 26)
- Museum operation 1934-1938, ca. 100 items (Box 26)
- Museum photographs 1935-1938, ca. 300 items (Box 27)
- Museum (proposed local) 1938, 4 items (Box 27)
- Museum (University of Virginia) 1933-1936, ca. 300 items (Box 27)
- Museum (University of Virginia) 1935-1936, ca. 250 items (Box 28)
- Museum (University of Virginia) 1936, ca. 200 items (Box 28)
  Includes Gari Melchers clipping.
- Music (general) 1920, ca. 15 items (Box 28)
- N Miscellaneous 1921-1945, ca. 100 items (Box 28)
- National Art Week 1940, ca. 100 items (Box 28)
  Includes correspondence of Mrs. Gari Melchers and President John Lloyd Newcomb
- National Association of Housing Officials 1937, 3 items (Box 28)
- National Council of Architectural Registration Boards 1921-1939, ca. 50 items (Box 28)
- National Council of Architectural Registration Boards 1929-1935, ca. 20 items (Box 28)
- National Youth Administration 1935-1938, ca. 50 items (Box 28)
- National Reserve Officers Training Corps 1941-1942, ca. 20 items (Box 29)
- New Pencil Points(Magazine) 1944, 1 item (Box 29)
- New York University 1934-1938, ca. 20 items (Box 29)
- Newcomb, Dr. (Bust of) 1934-1949, ca. 50 items (Box 29)
  Includes correspondence of John Lloyd Newcomb and Colgate W. Darden.
- Dr. John Lloyd Newcomb 1933-1945, ca. 100 letters (Box 30)
  see also: President's Office (John Lloyd Newcomb)
- Newspaper clippings 1930's, ca. 50 items (Box 29)
- Newspaper clippings 1930's, ca. 50 items (Box 29)
- Noland, William C. 1921-1935, ca. 20 items (Box 30)
- Notices 1938-1949, ca. 50 items (Box 30)
- Notices 1940, 5 items (Box 30)
- Notices 1940-1942, ca. 50 items (Box 30)
- Notices 1941-1942, ca. 50 items (Box 30)
- Notices 1942-1943, ca. 50 items (Box 30)
- Notices to Students 1927-1929, ca. 25 items (Box 30)
- Notices to Students 1935-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 30)
- Notices to Students 1937-1938, ca. 25 items (Box 30)
- Notices (used again) 1937, 2 items (Box 30)
- National Youth Administration (N.Y.A.) 1940-1942, 4 items (Box 30)
- National Youth Administration (workers) 1938-1940, ca. 25 items (Box 30)
- O Miscellaneous 1934-1950, ca. 20 items (Box 30)
- Obituary ca. 1930's and 1940's, ca. 50 items (Box 30)
- Office Equipment 1930-1931, ca. 20 items (Box 30)
- Old Age Annuities 1928, 3 items (Box 30)
- Old Notices 1944, 3 items (Box 30)
- P Miscellaneous 1927-1949, ca. 150 items (Box 31)
- Page-Barbour Lectures 1938, 3 items (Box 31)
- Painters and Painting 1931-1936, ca. 25 items (Box 31)
- Parker, Thomas C. 1933-1934, ca. 15 items (Box 31)
- Pending Applications 1922, ca. 10 items (Box 31)
- Pennsylvania State Board 1936, 2 items (Box 31)
- Pennsylvania, University of 1944, 1 item (Box 31)
- Peepbles and Ferguson, Architects 1914-1935, ca. 150 letters (Box 31)
  Concerning Virginia Museum of Fine Arts
- Periodicals 1928-1930, ca. 25 items (Box 31)
- Peery, Gov. George 1934-1935, ca. 20 items (Box 31)
- Perry, Shaw and Hepburn, Architects 1933-1937, ca. 20 items (Box 31)
- St. Peters Church (restoration) 1940-1941, ca. 10 items (Box 31)
- Photographers 1930-1935, 5 items (Box 31)
- Photographs (cases) 1935-1937, ca. 10 items (Box 31)
- Photograph and Lantern Slide Catalogue 1934-1937, ca. 100 items (Box 32)
- Photographs of Painting and Sculpture n.d., ca. 50 items (Box 32)
- Photographic survey 1932-1936, ca. 75 items (Box 32)
  Includes correspondence of John Lloyd Newcomb
- Piccirilli Bros. 1930-1931, 7 items (Box 32)
- Picnic (Annual Spring) 1939-1940, 5 items (Box 32)
- Piedmont Sanitorium 1933, 1 item (Box 32)
- Plaster Casts 1936, ca. 10 items (Box 32)
- Pollard, Gov. John Garland 1929-1934, ca. 150 items (Box 32)
- Pollard Portrait 1933-1934, ca. 15 items (Box 32)
- Portraits 1930-1931, ca. 10 items (Box 32)
- Portrait Painters 1931-1937, ca. 25 items (Box 32)
- Prefabricated Homes n.d., 1 item (Box 32)
- Prep. for Architecture n.d., 3 items (Box 32)
- President's Office (Edwin Anderson Alderman) 1927-1930, ca. 50 items (Box 32)
  see also: Alderman, Edwin Anderson
- President's Office (John Lloyd Newcomb) 1929-1938, ca. 150 items (Box 33)
  see also: Newcomb, John Lloyd
- Prints and Slides of Early American Architecture 1936-1938, ca. 15 items (Box 33)
- President's Report ca. 1941, ca. 10 items (Box 33)
- Prints (reproductions) n.d., 1 item (Box 33)
- Prints, orders, etc. 1938-1940, ca. 20 items (Box 33)
- Probation and Suspension 1939-1940, ca. 20 items (Box 33)
- Problems (Copies of) 1936-1939, ca. 50 items (Box 33)
- Problems (Copies of) 1939-1942, ca. 50 items (Box 33)
- Problems (4-5 hour) 1938, ca. 15 items (Box 33)
- Problems ca. 1930's, ca. 100 items (Box 33)
- Producer's Council 1930-1932, 5 items (Box 34)
- Professional Practice n.d., 3 items (Box 34)
- Programs 1927-1929, ca. 25 items (Box 34)
- Programs (Field House) 1938, ca. 20 items (Box 34)
- Programs (mimeographed) 1937-1938, ca. 25 items (Box 34)
- Prospective Students 1944, ca. 10 items (Box 34)
- Public Work of Art Project 1934-1937, ca. 25 items (Box 34)
- Public Works Administration (general) ca. 1930's, ca. 50 items (Box 34)
- Publicity 1919-1923, ca. 50 items (Box 34)
- Publicity for Exhibits n.d., ca. 10 items (Box 34)
- Publishers 1931-1932, ca. 10 items (Box 34)
- Purchase Orders 1940-1942, ca. 40 items (Box 35)
- Quarterly Report from University of Virginia 1929-1930, 1 item (Box 35)
- Quotations from various firms 1929-1931, 10 items (Box 35)
- R Miscellaneous 1927-1950, ca. 100 items (Box 35)
- Raven Society 1941, 3 items (Box 35)
- Reading required 1936, ca. 50 items (Box 35)
- Receipts 1938-1940, ca. 150 items (Box 35)
- Reciprocal Registration 1923, ca. 10 items (Box 35)
- Recitals 1919-1920, ca. 25 items (Box 35)
  Includes correspondence of Fiske Kimball.
- Recognition (official) of School 1933, 4 items (Box 35)
- Recommendations 1930-1937, ca. 25 items (Box 35)
- Recommendation (Poe Room, Raven Society) 1940-1941, ca. 50 items (Box 35)
- Record of Action n.d., ca. 10 items (Box 36)
- Record of Visitors (Museum) 1938-1943, 50 items (Box 36)
- Reese, Charles L. 1934-1935, ca. 20 items (Box 36)
- Registrar's Office 1927-1940, ca. 75 items (Box 36)
- Registrar (Miss Moran) 1940-1943, ca. 50 items (Box 36)
- Registration (New York) 1929-1933, 1 item (Box 36)
- Registration (Spring, 1939) 1939, 3 items (Box 36)
- Report (to Dean's Office) 1929, 1 item (Box 36)
- Report (to President's Office) 1932-1938, ca. 50 items (Box 36)
- Reports of Associations 1944, 1 item (Box 36)
- Report of Store Room 1928, 2 items (Box 36)
- Reproductions of paintings 1930-1938, ca. 25 items (Box 36)
- Requisitions to be sent 1930, ca. 20 items (Box 36)
- Requisitions (general) 1939-1940, ca. 50 items (Box 36)
- Reserved Book List n.d., ca. 50 items (Box 36)
- Restoration of Rotunda 1938, 2 items (Box 36)
- Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute 1931-1932, ca. 10 items (Box 36)
- Richard J[ames] A., Inc. 1931-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 36)
- Richmond Academy of Arts 1931-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 37)
- Robinson, Charles (Architect) 1920-1934, ca. 50 items (Box 37)
- Rockingham- Harrisonburg War Memorial 1944-1945, ca. 25 items (Box 37)
- Roerich Museum 1932-1933, 4 items (Box 37)
- Roller Steel Shelves 1938 (Box 2 items)
- Rome Prize 1940, ca. 10 items (Box 37)
- Rotch Traveling Scholarship 1920-1936, ca. 25 items (Box 37)
- Rotunda Busts 1930-1933, ca. 100 items (Box 37)
  Includes correspondence of Pollard.
- Royal Society of British Architects 1932-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 37)
- Reubens (Painting of Christ and St. John) 1920-1921, ca. 20 items (Box 37)
- Rucker's Estate (Dr. Newcomb and Museum) 1942, 3 items (Box 37)
- Rucker Memorial Library 1939-1941, ca. 15 items (Box 37)
- Rulings on courses 1944, 1 item (Box 37)
- Rustoy Studeback Chemical Co. 1936, 3 items (Box 37)
- S Miscellaneous 1921-1950, ca. 100 items (Box 37)
- Salary Scale (University of Virginia) 1929, 1 item (Box 38)
- Saunders, Peter 1931-1934, 5 items (Box 38)
- Savage, Louise 1939-1941, ca. 25 items (Box 38)
- Savedge, W.W. 1933-1935, ca. 10 items (Box 38)
- Schedule of Courses n.d., ca. 10 items (Box 38)
- Schedules 1929-1934, ca. 20 items (Box 38)
- Schiavoni, Mario 1931, ca. 10 items (Box 38)
- Scholar's (German) 1933, 3 items (Box 38)
- Scholarship 1932-1938, ca. 40 items (Box 38)
- Scholarship Equipment 1939-1941, ca. 20 items (Box 38)
- Scholarships (graduate) 1940, ca. 20 items (Box 38)
- Scholarships (recommendations) 1939-1940, ca. 15 items (Box 38)
- School correspondence 1932-1934, ca. 10 items (Box 38)
- School Equipment n.d., ca. 10 items (Box 38)
- School Equipment (correspondence) 1936-1940, ca. 100 items (Box 38)
- School Equipment (Makielski) 1940, 1 item (Box 38)
- School Furniture 1930, ca. 50 items (Box 38)
- Scripto Mfg. Co. 1933, 2 items (Box 38)
- Sievers, F. William 1930-1934, 20 items (Box 38)
- Sign painting n.d., 1 item (Box 38)
- Singleton, Thomas 1938-1939, ca. 10 items (Box 38)
- Slemp House (C. Bascom) 1930, ca. 20 items (Box 38)
- Slides 1933-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 38)
- Slides (lantern) 1937-1940, ca. 10 items (Box 39)
  see also: Lantern Slides
- Slides (future) 1933, 1934, ca. 10 items (Box 39)
- Slide Cabinet 1932-1938 (Box ca. 20 items)
- Smith (General F.H.) Statue 1930-1931, ca. 15 items (Box 39)
- Society Beaux Arts Architects 1931, 5 items (Box 39)
- Southern Art Projects 1937-1938, ca. 25 items (Box 39)
- Southern Arts Association 1942, 2 items (Box 39)
- Southern States Art League 1937-1938, ca. 25 items (Box 39)
- Southwestern State Hospital 1933, 1 item (Box 39)
- Special Events 1940-1941, ca. 25 items (Box 39)
- Special Notices 1942, 2 items (Box 39)
- Stair Treads 1938, 2 items (Box 29)
- Stanton Tower 1929, 1 item (Box 39)
- State Armory Commission 1935, 2 items (Box 39)
- State Art Commission (minutes) 1928-1931, ca. 25 items (Box 39)
- State Board Correspondence 1928
- State Board Correspondence 1929, ca. 25 items (Box 39)
- State Board Correspondence 1930, ca. 50 items (Box 39)
- State Board for the Examination...of...Architects 1944, 1 item (Box 39)
- State Board (C.G. Massie) 1933-1937, ca. 25 items (Box 39)
- State Board (miscellany) 1928-1930, ca. 50 items (Box 39)
- State Board (miscellany) n.d., ca. 20 items (Box 39)
- State Comptroller 1931-1932, 2 items (Box 39)
- State Development and Construction Commission 1934-1935, ca. 25 items (Box 40)
- State Flag n.d., 3 items (Box 40)
- State Library Building 1928-1933, ca. 20 items (Box 40)
  Includes correspondence of Harry Byrd and John Garland Pollard
- State Librarian 1930-1935, ca. 15 items (Box 40)
- State Seal 1930-1934, ca. 50 items (Box 40)
- State Teacher's College (East Radford) 1928-1933, 3 items (Box 40)
- State Teacher's College (Farmville) 1930-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 40)
- State Teacher's College (Harrisonburg) 1933, 1 item (Box 40)
- State Teacher's College (Fredericksburg) 1930-1934, ca. 20 items (Box 40)
- State Treasurer 1934, 1 item (Box 40)
- Stern, Philip 1928-1931, ca. 50 items (Box 40)
- Stern, Philip 1931-1935, ca. 200 items (Box 40)
- Stern, Philip 1933-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 40)
- Stern, re: Musuem of Fine Arts 1933-1948, ca. 50 items (Box 40)
- Strause, Henry P. 1941-1942, ca. 25 items (Box 40)
- Student Activities Building 1949, 1 item (Box 40)
- Student Corresopndence 1928-1942, ca. 100 items (Box 41)
- Student Courses 1936-1937, ca. 10 items (Box 41)
- Student (former, of Architectural School) 1937-1938, ca. 10 items (Box 41)
- Student (Graduates desirign positions) 1934, 3 items (Box 41)
- Student (number in Architecture) 1936, 2 items (Box 41)
- Student Excuses from classes for inspection trips 1940, 2 items (Box 41)
- Student Tours 1930-1932, ca. 10 items (Box 41)
- Student Fellowship 1941-1942, ca. 25 items (Box 41)
- Students 1927-1930, ca. 50 items (Box 41)
- Students opening new offices 1939, 4 items (Box 41)
- Students Records 1930-1937, ca. 100 items (Box 41)
- Sullivan Collection 1923, 3 items (Box 41)
- Summer Art School 1933-1937, ca. 25 items (Box 41)
- Summer School 1938, 3 items (Box 41)
- Summer School 1940-1942, ca. 25 items (Box 41)
- Summer School (catalogues) ca. 1940, ca. 25 items (Box 42)
- Summer School Data 1939-1940, ca. 25 items (Box 42)
- Summer Teaching 1920-1922, ca. 10 items (Box 42)
- Supplies (Drawing equipment) 1930-1937, ca. 20 items (Box 42)
- Superintendent of Buildings 1927-1931, ca. 20 items (Box 42)
- Superintendent of Buildings and Grounds 1931-1938, ca. 75 items (Box 42)
  Includes correspondence of John Lloyd Newcomb.
- Supreme Court Building 1935-1936, ca. 10 items (Box 42)
- Syracuse University 1927, 1 item (Box 42)
- T Miscellaneous 1929-1945, ca. 50 items (Box 42)
- Taylor, Wickman 1928-1934, ca. 25 items (Box 42)
- Taylor and Fisher, Architects 1932-1935, ca. 25 items (Box 42)
- Telegrams 1928-1929, ca. 20 items (Box 42)
- Telegrams and Statements 1936, ca. 20 items (Box 42)
- Termites 1935, 4 items (Box 42)
- Theatre (University) 1934, 10 items (Box 42)
  Includes letters to John Lloyd Newcomb
- Temple, W.M. (Owens-Illinois Glass) 1938-1939, ca. 20 items (Box 43)
- Tourist Market (University of Virginia) 1930, 2 items (Box 43)
- Turner, Joseph (Hollins College) 1934, 3 items (Box 43)
- Tuthill Advertising Agency 1929, ca. 10 items (Box 43)
- U Miscellaneous 1936-1944, 3 items (Box 43)
- University Civilian Defense 1942, ca. 10 items (Box 43)
- University of Michigan 1930, 2 items (Box 43)
- University of New York 1928-1935, ca. 10 items (Box 43)
- University Notices 1939, 2 items (Box 43)
  Includes letter of John Lloyd Newcomb
- University of Richmond 1930-1931, ca. 10 items (Box 43)
- University Travel League 1930, 3 items (Box 43)
- University of Virginia 1931-1935, ca. 25 items (Box 43)
- University of Virginia (general file) 1919-1922 (Box ca. 100 items)
- V Miscellaneous 1933-1945, ca. 50 items (Box 43)
- Valentine, Edward V. 1930, ca. 10 items (Box 43)
- Veterans 1945, 2 items (Box 43)
- Virginia Antiquities 1933-1935 (Box 2 items)
- Virginia Art Allliance 1934-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 43)
- Virginia Manuel Labor School 1933, 1 item (Box 43)
- Virginia Home and Industrial School for Boys 1933, 2 items (Box 43)
- Virginia Home and Industrial School for Girls 1933, 1 item (Box 43)
- Virginia Home and Industrial School for Colored Girls 1933, 2 items (Box 43)
- Virginia Military Institute 1930-1933, ca. 25 items (Box 43)
- Virginia Museum of Fine Ats 1932-1934, ca. 100 items (Box 43)
- Virginia Museum of Fine Arts 1935-1944, ca. 75 items (Box 44)
- Virginia Musem of Fine Arts (Advisory Committee) n.d., 1 item (Box 44)
- Virginia Normal and Industrial Instiute. 1933, 1 item (Box 44)
- Virgina Polytechnic Institute 1929-1934, ca. 15 items (Box 444)
- Virginia Quarterly 1929, 1 item (Box 44)
- Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind Children 1929-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 44)
- Virginia School for the Colored Deaf and Blind Children 1933, 1 item (Box 44)
- Virginia School Supply Co. 1924-1925, ca. 15 items (Box 44)
- Virginia Society of Agriculture 1939-1942, ca. 50 items (Box 44)
- Virginia State Epileptic Colony 1930-1934, ca. 20 items (Box 44)
- Virginia Truck Experiment 1928-1934, 4 items (Box 44)
- Visitors 1927-1928, 3 items (Box 44)
- W Miscellaneous 1927-1950 (Box 44)
- Wakefield Memorial Association 1930-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 44)
- Walker, Clifford L. 1933-1934, ca. 20 items (Box 44)
- War Memorial Commission 1930-1933, ca. 50 items (Box 44)
- Water Colors 1922, ca. 10 items (Box 44)
- Western State Hospital 1929-1933, ca. 10 items (Box 44)
- Weyhe, E. (Publisher) 1930-1938, ca. 50 items (Box 44)
- William and Mary College 1920-1934, ca. 100 items (Box 44)
- William and Mary College (John S. Bryan, Pres.) 1934, 3 items (Box 45)
  see also: Bryan, John S.
- William and Mary College (Library Building) 1928-1930, ca. 25 items (Box 45)
- William and Mary College (Wren, Spotsford Building) 1921-1932, ca. 150 items (Box 45)
- Williamsburg Advisory Board 1933-1935, ca. 25 items (Box 45)
- Williamsburg Inc. 1935-1940, ca. 20 items (Box 45)
- Williamsburg (Trips, Sketching, etc.) 1934-1937, ca. 50 items (Box 45)
- Wilson, H.W. Co. 1931-1932, ca. 20 items (Box 45)
- Work of Art (for sale) 1935-1937, ca. 20 items (Box 45)
- Woods, Francis S. 1938, 4 items (Box 45)
- XY Miscellaneous 1938-1950, ca. 50 items (Box 45)
- Young's Art Shop 1934-1938, ca. 20 items (Box 45)
- Young's Art Shop 1944-1945 (Box 3 items)
- Z Miscallaneous 1936-1947, ca. 50 items (Box 45)
- Zetter, Emil 1934, 5 items (Box 45)
- Miscellaneous pamphlets n.d., ca. 30 items (Box 45)
- Unidentified materials n.d., ca. 400 items (Box 46)